<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Joanne的博客</title>
    <link>http://yoursite.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <description>some fragments</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:25:47 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>http://hexo.io/</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique | LaTeX——一款麻烦却真的好看的排版系统</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/latex/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/latex/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;第一次用LeTaX的经历是让我终生难忘的。参加了19年1月的美赛，临近最后提交时间我都不断地在做着排版上的调整，机房的椅子没有靠背，从前一天傍晚肝到第二天早上，腰酸背痛，不知疲倦。所以想借此机会整理一下，指不定哪天会再用上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##下载与安装&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>第一次用LeTaX的经历是让我终生难忘的。参加了19年1月的美赛，临近最后提交时间我都不断地在做着排版上的调整，机房的椅子没有靠背，从前一天傍晚肝到第二天早上，腰酸背痛，不知疲倦。所以想借此机会整理一下，指不定哪天会再用上。</p><p>##下载与安装</p><p><i class="chain"></i>下载<a href="https://www.latex-project.org/get/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">地址</a><br>ps.</p><p><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-square"></i>in lists</li>耗时比较久（软件比较大），安装时以管理员身份运行。</p><p><li><i class="fa-li fa fa-square"></i>in lists</li>检查是否配置系统环境变量。控制面板-系统和安全-系统-高级系统设置-环境变量-系统变量-Path。</p><p><i class="question-circle"></i>环境变量是什么呢？其实我们可以把它理解为【系统的视线范围】，没错，配置进入了环境变量的程序，就等于是进入了系统的视线范围，打开DOS命令窗口后输入程序名，系统就会把在其视线内的（环境变量内）的程序找出来，如果程序没有配置进入环境的变量的话，那系统自然就找不到。（摘自 <a href="https://jingyan.baidu.com/article/a17d5285c9b0c48099c8f26a.html）" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://jingyan.baidu.com/article/a17d5285c9b0c48099c8f26a.html）</a></p><p>博主用的是 <strong>TeXLive</strong> + <strong>Atom</strong> ，TeXLive自带编辑器TexWorks editor，不过我更喜欢Atom，通过安装以下几个包：</p><ul><li><strong>language-latex</strong></li><li><strong>latex</strong></li><li><strong>pdf-view</strong><br>可以实现舒适编辑和即时预览。<br><img src="/2019/03/03/latex/1.png" width="60%" style="float:center; border:none"><br><img src="/2019/03/03/latex/2.png" width="60%" style="float:center; border:none"><br><img src="/2019/03/03/latex/3.png" width="60%" style="float:center; border:none"><br>在tex文件下进行编辑， <strong>ctrl + alt + B</strong> 来生成/更新PDF文档，或 <strong>Packages-LaTeX-Build</strong> 也可以达到同样效果。</li></ul><p>本文梳理过程中参考了 <a href="https://blog.csdn.net/discoverer100/article/details/69257952" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://blog.csdn.net/discoverer100/article/details/69257952</a><br>关于latex的入门参考资料 <a href="http://juke.outofmemory.cn/entry/107516" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://juke.outofmemory.cn/entry/107516</a><br>关于latex的命令汇总 <a href="https://blog.csdn.net/young951023/article/details/79601664" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://blog.csdn.net/young951023/article/details/79601664</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/latex/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>爱的模样 ——《さよならの朝に約束の花をかざろう》影评</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:18:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/ogp.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:center; border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://movie.douban.com/subj
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/ogp.jpg" style="float:center; border:none"></p><blockquote><p><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/27083561/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>豆瓣评分 7.0</strong></a></p></blockquote><p><font size="5">故</font>事讲述了一个长生种族——伊鲁奥夫「イオルフ」，他们外貌与人类相似，以织布为生，名曰希比奥尔「ヒビオル」，一直以来过着简单和平与世隔绝的生活。一次梅萨蒂国王派军队侵袭，并抓走其中一位女性蕾莉亚，打算将其与本国王子结为连理，以加强国家势力。离别的一族彻底支离破碎，主角玛琪亚幸存下来，并与在森林中出生便孤身一人的婴儿相遇，故事于此开始。</p><p><font color="#A83361" size="5"><strong>主要人物关系</strong></font><br><br><br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/c01.jpg" width="20%" style="float:left; border:none"><strong>玛琪亚</strong>：没有父母，伊鲁奥夫<br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/c02.jpg" width="20%" style="float:left; border:none"><strong>艾瑞尔</strong>：森林中的婴儿，被玛琪亚带走并抚养长大<br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/c03.jpg" width="20%" style="float:left; border:none"><strong>蕾莉亚</strong>：伊鲁奥夫的幸存者，因梅萨蒂王的命令而被抓走<br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/c04.jpg" width="20%" style="float:left; border:none"><strong>克里姆</strong>：伊鲁奥夫的幸存者，一直爱着蕾莉亚<br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/logo.png" width="20%" style="float:left; border:none">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;影片中的长老对玛琪亚说：“爱上一个人，便是孤独的开始。”对于长生种族来说，需要经历无数个离别。玛琪亚与收留她的赫尔姆农场的女主人米多一家一起面对家犬的离世，她保持着来时同样的15岁容颜。因为自身不变的体格与外貌，她不能在一地久留，只能带着艾瑞尔辗转各地，她没做过母亲，却为艾瑞尔努力扮演着母亲角色，“我不会再哭了，因为我是母亲啊”一句里充满着一个15岁女孩的决心。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;爱是陪伴，玛琪亚和蕾莉亚都有自己的孩子，不同的是蕾莉亚诞下孩子后就不被允许相见，虽然两人都说满脑子只想着自己的孩子。但是，蕾莉亚与梅多梅尔相见后，没有拥抱的冲动，相反，她奔向了天空。梅多梅尔一直以来对母亲的想象也在此刻圆满。相较之下，玛琪亚与艾瑞尔相伴了很长的时间，离别到再次相遇，艾瑞尔舍不得并对玛琪亚喊出了“妈妈”两个字。“不管你叫我什么，那都会是我的名字”，陪伴的过程中，艾瑞尔不断长大，心境也随之转变，得到了爱与不能保护母亲的不甘心，带着年少时期种种复杂的情绪，他离开了玛琪亚的陪伴。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;爱是不断延续的，艾瑞尔受尽滋养，以爱创造了自己的归所，他与人相爱，保卫国家。即便不能与所爱之人永远相伴，存在过的痕迹会影响和伴随着个体一同前行。因为艾瑞尔的存在，才有了继续带着希望生活下去的玛琪亚。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;爱不是占有，不是为得回报的自私想法。年少的艾瑞尔离家去参军，剩下偷偷大哭的玛琪亚，她做到了放手，把不舍留给了自己。同为流浪在外的克里姆也为了自己深爱的蕾莉亚一而再，再而三地采取营救行动。克里姆的爱没有变，而失去了同伴的蕾莉亚将爱倾注到了自己未曾谋面的梅多梅尔身上，离开前只请求克里姆带她见一面自己的孩子。克里姆一个人爱了太久，没有他想，而彼人非此人，等待他的只能是孤独的离去。克里姆将所有爱灌注在了蕾莉亚身上，不求回报，因此绝不是自私的，可最后却对蕾莉亚抱有了私有化的想法，其中隐含着无法实现自己愿望的无可奈何。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;三个伊鲁奥夫的不同遭遇呈现了爱不同的样子，互相交织，形成冲突和对比。谁的爱都未得圆满，而与长老警告相背的女孩将爱给了艾瑞尔，她的人生轨迹因爱而延续，爱与她的长寿一同延续下去。容颜依旧的蕾莉亚来到垂危的艾瑞尔身边，做了最后的道别。<u>她历尽沧桑，最后却是少女般咧开大嘴哭泣，她最后的哭泣带来蒲公英，蒲公英就是注定离别的生命。</u>（鹦鹉史航）因为孤独而相遇的生命经历爱的过程，就宣告离别。玛琪亚说：“只要我还活着，艾瑞尔的“希比奥尔”就会继续。”或许，所爱之人将以另一种形式陪伴她。</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;爱的形式和阶段在较古代的背景中呈现，在嵌入离别一族设定的同时，爱的共鸣强烈突出却又如抽丝剥茧般贯穿整部作品，美中不足是时间段与场景的衔接不流畅，原因觉得是载体的时长要求导致无法做到解释。母爱本身就是渗透在生活中方方面面的东西，以艾瑞尔的生命长度去诠释爱的样子，在只有不到120分钟的作品中确是有难度的。<br><img src="/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/bg.jpg" style="float:center; border:none"></p><p><font color="#FF8F33">看了部分评论感觉大家普遍喷得多，博主比较感性，影片初听到音乐眼泪就<strong>劈里啪啦</strong>留下来了，所以评价实在也是我个人的想法，就当我是无脑夸吧：)</font><br>影片中除了伊鲁奥夫还有龙也是长寿一族，这一元素既是梅萨蒂侵略的致因，在中期映衬蕾莉亚的内心想法，也在后期为影片起到了画龙点睛的作用。（看的时候没做很多关注，所以不细展开了，今后回顾作品会考虑补充）</p><p><font color="#3994EB">单纯的夸几个方面，音乐、画面、声优真的很棒！冈妈赛高，至今没有看过未闻花名的我实在没什么资格说这句话，但是——<font size="5">冈妈赛高！</font></font><br><br></p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width="298" height="52" src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=2&id=536623722&auto=1&height=32"></iframe>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/03/zhaohuaxishi/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEWS Article | Barbarians grow up</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2018/09/18/barbarians/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2018/09/18/barbarians/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 14:08:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;h1 id=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#写在前面&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;写在前面&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;私募股权（PE）&lt;br&gt;Venture capital, Growth capital, Leveraged buyout(
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="写在前面"><a href="#写在前面" class="headerlink" title="写在前面"></a>写在前面</h1><p>私募股权（PE）<br>Venture capital, Growth capital, Leveraged buyout(L.B.O)</p><blockquote><p>Venture capital(VC 风险投资) small private startups<br>features: high risk seed funding<br>goal: move firms from private its private ownership into the public sector cash out their stake and move on into the next company<br>example: 3i</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Growth capital(Development capital 成长资本)<br>features: already large or maybe a listed plc, need experienced professionals, expertise management<br>goal: help the firm growth</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Leverage buyout(L.B.O 杠杆收购)<br><img src="/2018/09/18/barbarians/barbarians.jpg" width="50%" align="center"></p></blockquote><center>‘Barbarians at the gate’</center><center><font size="0.8">图源: <a href="https://audiobookstore.com/audiobooks/barbarians-at-the-gate-1.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://audiobookstore.com/audiobooks/barbarians-at-the-gate-1.aspx</a></font></center><blockquote><p>features: stodgy public company - private hand<br>goal: gobble up a firm/ make improvements and then sell back to the market at higher price<br>fund, private equity house, venture capital trust, exchange-traded fund(交易所交易基金 London Stock Exchange)<br>for retail investors<br><img src="/2018/09/18/barbarians/example.png" alt="The image link is failed!"></p></blockquote><center>The Real Estate Value Matrix</center><center><font size="0.8">图源: <a href="https://startupsventurecapital.com/real-estate-private-equity-technologys-next-victims-part-1-58a7fe77dc81" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://startupsventurecapital.com/real-estate-private-equity-technologys-next-victims-part-1-58a7fe77dc81</a></font></center><h1 id="As-private-equity-firms-mature-the-way-they-buy-and-sell-is-changing"><a href="#As-private-equity-firms-mature-the-way-they-buy-and-sell-is-changing" class="headerlink" title="As private-equity firms mature, the way they buy and sell is changing"></a><center><b>As private-equity firms mature, the way they buy and sell is changing</b></center></h1><p><center><font color="#A4A4A4" size="2"><b>They are reshaping Wall Street’s ecosystem</b></font></center><br><img src="/2018/09/18/barbarians/0.jpg" width="80%" align="center"><br>“SELL in May and go away,” say the denizens of Wall Street, and to the usual summer <font color="DeepPink">lethargy(慵懒)</font> is added the excuse of a heatwave. But for those working in private equity, there is no let-up. The “shops”, as private-equity funds like to call themselves, are stuffed with money and raising more: \$1.1trn in “dry powder” ready to spend around the world, according to Preqin, a consultancy, with another \$950bn being raised by 3,050 firms.</p><blockquote><p>“五月清仓，完事离场” 大量pe却松懈不得，一个个’shop’跃跃欲试</p></blockquote><p>So hot is the market that there are rumours of money being turned away. Even the firms themselves, which receive fees linked to assets under management, cannot <font color="DeepPink">fathom(看穿)</font> how to use all that may come their way. It is not for want of trying. The year to date has seen nearly 1,000 acquisitions (see chart 1). Health care has been particularly vibrant (see next article).<br><img src="/2018/09/18/barbarians/1.png" width="50%" align="center"><br>Even more noteworthy than the volume of money pouring into private equity is the way the business is maturing. Banks are reconfiguring their operations to serve such a transaction-heavy clientele. Limited partners—the public-pension schemes, sovereign-wealth funds, <font color="DeepPink">endowments(捐赠)</font> and family offices that provide the bulk of private-equity investment—are playing more active roles. It all adds up to a <font color="DeepPink">stealthy(秘密的)</font>, but significant, reshaping of the financial ecosystem.</p><p>Data on returns are <font color="DeepPink">patchy(零散的)</font>. Odd measures are often used to gauge performance and disclosure is <font color="DeepPink">intermittent(断断续续的)</font>. But there is plenty of reason to believe that private-equity funds have done well in the past decade. Low interest rates have favoured their debt-heavy business model. Rising asset prices have made it easy to sell for large gains.</p><blockquote><p>大量资金进入，多方介入（包括公共养老金、主权财富基金、捐赠基金、家族财富办公室等），重塑了金融生态。虽然数据报告、披露都很零散，时有时无，但不得不承认这项业务一直表现不俗，并在走向成熟。</p></blockquote><p>And some recent clouds on the horizon have <font color="DeepPink">dissipated(使…消散)</font>. <font color="DeepPink">Mooted(酝酿)</font> tax reforms would have stopped private-equity firms from deducting the interest they pay on debt from their taxable income and forced their managers to pay the personal-tax rate on their investment profits (or “carried interest”), rather than the lower capital-gains rate. In the event, however, the new rules brought in last year did not touch carried interest at all and only slightly reduced the benefits of debt.</p><p>Another fear had been that regulations would become less supportive. Jay Clayton, who took over at the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) last year, made it clear that he wanted to see a shift towards public markets. He noted that the loss of companies to private equity had denied opportunities to small investors. A flurry of public offerings followed his appointment, including sales by private-equity firms. But the burdens of being listed remain heavy. These include <font color="DeepPink">onerous(繁重的)</font> filing requirements and the knowledge that routine business decisions may become the subject of <font color="DeepPink">caustic(刻薄的，激烈的)</font> public debate.</p><p>The result is that the value of public companies being taken private continues to rise (see chart 2). The figures understate the trend, since they omit the growing number of large companies selling off divisions to private-equity firms. These deals attract little attention—which is partly the point. Headquarters do not move; senior executives keep their jobs. Recent examples include the decision by J.M. Smucker, a food company, to sell its baking business to Brynwood Partners and GE’s move to sell its industrial-engines division to Advent International. Similarly unremarked is the rising number of transactions in which one private-equity firm sells to another, rather than listing an asset on the public markets.</p><blockquote><p>税务税盾和监管的调整最终导致上市公司被私有化的规模持续提升。</p></blockquote><p><img src="/2018/09/18/barbarians/2.png" width="50%" align="center"><br>Private equity’s growing <font color="DeepPink">heft(重量)</font> has knock-on effects throughout the financial sector. Goldman Sachs has 25 merger bankers assigned to private-equity firms, working on deals alongside colleagues who focus on specific industries. Its analysts monitor 5,500 private-equity holdings—50% more than the number of listings on the American public markets. The other big institutional banks, such as Morgan Stanley and JPMorgan Chase, are just as attentive to private equity.</p><p>The most significant change may be in private equity’s investor base. In the past two years the number of limited partners with more than \$1bn invested has grown from 304 to 359. Together they account for \$1.5trn—half of all private-equity money, according to Preqin. And this statistic does not fully capture their growing activism. As well as placing cash in private-equity funds, they increasingly “co-invest”—ie, take direct stakes in a buy-out.</p><p>The advantage for limited partners is that they avoid management fees—often 2% annually, plus 20% of profits. Private-equity funds gain from being less reliant on each other. Not long ago, large deals often required several funds to collaborate. The purchase of Nielsen Media in 2006, for example, involved seven. That alarmed antitrust regulators, complicated management and made it hard to exit from investments, since many potential buyers were already co-owners. The value of deals done by more than one private-equity firm has fallen by half since the Nielsen deal. Even when firms work together, the average number involved is smaller than it was.</p><p>For the biggest deals, private-equity firms are today making acquisitions solo and then syndicating large stakes through co-investments to limited partners. Notable among numerous recent examples are Blackstone’s purchase of Thomson Reuters’ finance and risk division in January for \$20bn, and Carlyle’s of the specialty-chemicals division of Akzo Nobel, a Dutch multinational, in March for \$12bn. The process often begins with a phone call by a private-equity firm to big, sophisticated investors such as GIC, Singapore’s sovereign-wealth fund, or CPP Investment Board, a giant Canadian pension fund. They can quickly put together teams to analyse transactions. Smaller limited partners are brought in later if needed, along with select outsiders, notably family offices.</p><p>This trend does not just reduce risk for private-equity managers. It also underlines a change in financial markets. Why should companies accept the costs and scrutiny that come with selling shares to the general public when there is a sophisticated, rich, private alternative? And when the time comes for one private-equity owner to sell, another private-equity fund can put together such a network to buy. Brokers and exchanges developed a century ago to help companies tap money where it lay—in individual pockets. Today that capital increasingly lies elsewhere.</p><blockquote><p>私募股权公司势力的增长，投资群体增多，他们所占的金额也很大。现在在大型收购案上大多是私募独揽，之后再卖股权给投资合伙人。这与尼尔森案例中多家基金合作相比，降低了风险（引起反垄断监管机构关注，管理变得复杂，推出投资变得困难）。如今有资金充裕渠道成熟的私募，大费周章公开募股是否还有必要（成本和审查限制）</p></blockquote><p>来自 <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/07/26/as-private-equity-firms-mature-the-way-they-buy-and-sell-is-changing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/07/26/as-private-equity-firms-mature-the-way-they-buy-and-sell-is-changing</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2018/09/18/barbarians/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEWS Article | 数字时代的浪漫</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/29/news-modern-love/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/29/news-modern-love/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 07:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;h1 id=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#写在前面&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;写在前面&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;栏目命名为NEWS Article，旨在览读深度且有趣的新闻。此次的文章来源The Economist（经济学人），以后应该
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="写在前面"><a href="#写在前面" class="headerlink" title="写在前面"></a>写在前面</h1><p>栏目命名为NEWS Article，旨在览读深度且有趣的新闻。此次的文章来源The Economist（经济学人），以后应该也会有别的，但是大多以英文为主。原文中会补充部分解释，段落后有概括性的翻译和总结。</p><h1 id="Modern-Love"><a href="#Modern-Love" class="headerlink" title="Modern Love"></a><center><b>Modern Love</b></center></h1><p><center><font color="#A4A4A4" size="2"><b>Online dating has changed the search for a mate, for better more than for worse</b></font></center></p><h5 id="Online-dating"><a href="#Online-dating" class="headerlink" title="Online dating"></a>Online dating</h5><p>THE internet has transformed the way people work and communicate. It has <font color="DeepPink">upended(颠覆)</font> industries, from entertainment to retailing. But its most profound effect may well be on the biggest decision that most people make—choosing a mate.</p><p><img src="/2018/08/29/news-modern-love/ml.jpg" alt="The image link is failed!"></p><p>In the early 1990s the notion of meeting a partner online seemed <font color="DeepPink">freakish(古怪的)</font>, and not a little <font color="DeepPink">pathetic(可悲的)</font>. Today, in many places, it is normal. Smartphones have put virtual bars in people’s pockets, where singletons can <font color="DeepPink">mingle(交往)</font> free from the constraints of social or physical geography. Globally, at least 200m people use digital dating services every month. In America more than a third of marriages now start with an online match-up. The internet is the second-most-popular way for Americans to meet people of the opposite sex, and is fast catching up with real-world “friend of a friend” introductions.</p><p>Digital dating is a massive social experiment, conducted on one of humanity’s most <font color="DeepPink">intimate(亲密的)</font> and vital processes. Its effects are only just starting to become visible.</p><blockquote><p>在上世纪90年代早期dating online看起来是很古怪的，甚至让人感觉很可悲。现在就变成了很通常的情况：只要带着手机，不用顾及地理上的距离，两人也可以自由地交往。在全球范围内，每个月就有至少200个million（2亿人）在dating online。在美国，三分之一的婚姻都是靠网络匹配来的。这种方式在美国已经仅次于“朋友的朋友”，能够快速结交异性。</p></blockquote><h5 id="When-Harry-clicked-on-Sally"><a href="#When-Harry-clicked-on-Sally" class="headerlink" title="When Harry clicked on Sally"></a>When Harry clicked on Sally</h5><p>Meeting a mate over the internet is fundamentally different from meeting one offline. In the physical world, partners are found in family networks or among circles of friends and colleagues. Meeting a friend of a friend is the <font color="DeepPink">norm(常态)</font>. People who meet online are overwhelmingly likely to be strangers. As a result, dating digitally offers much greater choice. A bar, <font color="DeepPink">choir(合唱团)</font> or office might have a few tens of potential partners for any one person. Online there are tens of thousands.</p><p>This greater choice—plus the fact that digital connections are made only with mutual consent—makes the digital dating market far more efficient than the offline kind. For some, that is bad news. Because of the gulf in pickiness between the sexes, a few straight men are doomed never to get any matches at all. On Tantan, a Chinese app, men express interest in 60% of women they see, but women are interested in just 6% of men; this dynamic means that 5% of men never receive a match. In offline dating, with a much smaller pool of men to fish from, straight women are more likely to couple up with men who would not get a look-in online.</p><p>For most people, however, digital dating offers better outcomes. Research has found that marriages in America between people who meet online are likely to last longer; such couples profess to be happier than those who met offline. The <font color="DeepPink">whiff(原意：喷 此处引申为：……引发的影响)</font> of moral panic surrounding dating apps is vastly overblown. Precious little evidence exists to show that opportunities online are encouraging <font color="DeepPink">infidelity(不忠行为)</font>. In America, divorce rates climbed until just before the advent of the internet, and have fallen since.</p><p>Online dating is a particular <font color="DeepPink">boon(福音)</font> for those with very particular requirements. Jdate allows daters to filter out matches who would not consider converting to Judaism, for instance. A vastly bigger market has had dramatic results for same-sex daters in particular. In America, 70% of gay people meet their partners online. This searchable spectrum of sexual diversity is a boon: more people can find the intimacy they seek.</p><p>There are problems with the modern way of love, however. Many users complain of stress when confronted with the brutal realities of the digital meat market, and their place within it. Negative emotions about body image existed before the internet, but they are amplified when strangers can issue snap judgments on attractiveness. Digital dating has been linked to depression. The same problems that afflict other digital platforms recur in this realm, from <font color="DeepPink">scams(骗局)</font> to fake accounts: 10% of all newly created dating profiles do not belong to real people.</p><p>This new world of romance may also have unintended consequences for society. The fact that online daters have so much more choice can break down barriers: evidence suggests that the internet is boosting interracial marriages by bypassing homogenous social groups. But daters are also more able to choose partners like themselves. Assortative mating, the process whereby people with similar education levels and incomes pair up, already shoulders some of the blame for income inequality. Online dating may make the effect more pronounced: education levels are displayed <font color="DeepPink">prominently(突出地)</font> on dating profiles in a way they would never be offline. It is not hard to imagine dating services of the future matching people by preferred traits, as determined by uploaded genomes. Dating firms also suffer from an inherent conflict of interest. Perfect matching would leave them <font color="DeepPink">bereft of(失去)</font> paying customers.</p><p>The domination of online dating by a handful of firms and their algorithms is another source of worry. Dating apps do not benefit from exactly the same sort of network effects as other tech platforms: a person’s friends do not need to be on a specific dating site, for example. But the feedback loop between large pools of data, generated by ever-growing numbers of users attracted to an ever-improving product, still exists. The entry into the market of Facebook, armed with data from its 2.2bn users, will provide clues as to whether online dating will inexorably consolidate into fewer, larger platforms.</p><blockquote><p>Modern love毋庸置疑的，存在利弊还有隐患。利主要体现在配对更加自由多样，但是由于异性挑剔的程度不同，会导致总有一小部分人找不到配对的人。利的另外一点是，即便存在一些虚假身份，信息相对现实见面还是更加公开透明的，依此大家能够尽可能达到“门当户对”。对于服务方也就是公司来说，越来越高效的服务反而又会减少他们的客户，这种利益冲突的现象在寿险上也存在。还有一点是受制于算法，大量的匹配结果都受服务方影响，说的难听点，服务方是可以在一定程度上操纵配对的dating场地、结果等等。</p></blockquote><h5 id="While-you-were-swiping"><a href="#While-you-were-swiping" class="headerlink" title="While you were swiping"></a>While you were swiping</h5><p>But even if the market does not become ever more concentrated, the process of coupling (or not) has unquestionably become more centralised. Romance used to be a distributed activity which took place in a <font color="DeepPink">profusion(充足的)</font> of bars, clubs, churches and offices; now enormous numbers of people rely on a few companies to meet their mate. That hands a small number of coders, tweaking the algorithms that determine who sees whom across the virtual bar, tremendous power to engineer mating outcomes. In authoritarian societies especially, the prospect of algorithmically arranged marriages ought to cause some disquiet. Competition offers some protection against such a possibility; so too might greater transparency over the principles used by dating apps to match people up.</p><p>Yet such concerns should not obscure the good that comes from the modern way of romance. The right partners can elevate and nourish each other. The wrong ones can ruin both their lives. Digital dating offers millions of people a more efficient way to find a good mate. That is something to love.</p><blockquote><p>最后谈到伴侣结合过程的集中化，配对结果是把握在少数几个大公司手里，归根究底是把握在调整算法的那几个程序员手里。Algorithmically arranged mating会引起社会争议，但是竞争会促使环境和配对原则更加透明。总的来说Modern Love的方式是利大于弊的。</p></blockquote><p>来自 <a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2018/08/18/modern-love" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.economist.com/leaders/2018/08/18/modern-love</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/29/news-modern-love/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>我只是想要点“真”的东西</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/21/%E4%B8%80%E5%87%BA%E5%A5%BD%E6%88%8F/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/21/%E4%B8%80%E5%87%BA%E5%A5%BD%E6%88%8F/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 04:53:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;h1 id=&quot;我很想见你-起初我不知道那其中的意义&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#我很想见你-起初我不知道那其中的意义&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;我很想见你 起初我不知道那其中的意义&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;我很想见你 起初我不知道那其中的意义&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="我很想见你-起初我不知道那其中的意义"><a href="#我很想见你-起初我不知道那其中的意义" class="headerlink" title="我很想见你 起初我不知道那其中的意义"></a>我很想见你 起初我不知道那其中的意义</h1><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;我有一个未曾正式见过面的学长。我和他已经维持了将近两年半的网友关系，关系至亲则是在近半年。后来很自然地，我想见见他，不过因为种种原因，都没有达成“面基”。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;我想在这里细谈的是，我想与之相见的原因、过程中心境的转变。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;起初我很单纯地想约他出门，另外我对他的声音很有好感，这件事作为朋友我想当面跟他再说一遍。我认为许多事情值得我当面去传达，因为他要出国了。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;他曾经在我最需要安慰的时候，以最远的距离，作出了最暖心的行为，简单来说，他愿意在半夜不睡，听我倒苦水。之后我也真实地有一颗想要恋爱，想要拥抱一个人的心。我说我可以在你走之前抱抱你么，被他用一句“能不能见面还是个问题”蒙混过去。我渐渐感受到我们之间除了每晚的几盘游戏，没有其他继续相处下去的理由，他不再关心我的事情，每句回复都是玩笑话。我行动在前，主动删除了我们之间所有的联系途径。</p><h1 id="我很想见你-我想延续我们的关系"><a href="#我很想见你-我想延续我们的关系" class="headerlink" title="我很想见你 我想延续我们的关系"></a>我很想见你 我想延续我们的关系</h1><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;冷静了一个礼拜，在这一个礼拜里，要对他的在线视而不见，我做出那个行为的同时，心有一阵绞痛。我决定顺从最单纯的想法————我想和他正常地玩会儿游戏。再过了两天以后，我才慢慢跟他谈开许多事情，但是实际上还是有件事情记挂在心，那就是我们仿佛要渐行渐远的关系。这种迹象让我万分焦虑，我尝试主动改变，我想通过见面，找到新的point，给我们之间找到延续友谊的可能。他让我别多想，也不愿正面回答我“会不会想起我”的问题。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;“那你还是顺其自然好，别让我影响你的生活”是他抛给我的最让我心痛的话。这世界上有“正面刚”的人，有沉默的人，也有像他这样的人。或许除了那个我想要的回答，其他任何答案都会让我难过……我又是一阵心绞痛。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;掉下了眼泪。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;我告诉自己必须耐心点，甚至让自己死了心，我试问自己为什么总想那么多，还是恰逢七夕前后……有那无处安放的嫉妒心在搅合。我想这多少跟家庭因素有关，不禁又生起一种自卑与愧疚。</p><h1 id="我很想见你-在现实中与你沉默相对"><a href="#我很想见你-在现实中与你沉默相对" class="headerlink" title="我很想见你 在现实中与你沉默相对"></a>我很想见你 在现实中与你沉默相对</h1><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;在《一出好戏》中，珊珊说想要点“真”的东西，她哭着喊着，站在周遭之内，心却好似在别处发狂，好荒谬，又好真实。看完电影的第二天早晨，我看到高中班里男生一起彻夜轰趴的消息，看着他们的集体照，我感动之余又好羡慕。我时不时抬头回应着讲课的老师，心却好似在别处发狂。我在地铁上不想回家，站在月台上向各种人发消息，在众多面孔里，众多沉默里，众多可能性里。终于有人回复我，给了我最迫切想要的东西，一次即刻的见面。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;我在月台上高兴地跺起了脚，像个孩子。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;这是一次突然的，迟到很久的见面，一个有趣的朋友（Q先生）。我们两个没有去成原定的书展，只是在附近一起吃了晚饭。相见的过程中我们没有互相询问近况，他说着现成的琐事，我也能任意应合，其他时候我们多半沉默。这是一次多么舒适的会面，我的心好久没这般安宁。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;在破船边上，火把被丢到了珊珊脚边，珊珊说“我就再信一次你这个骗子”，说罢便把火把丢向破船。珊珊的哭喊声只有马进听到了，也只有马进被叫醒了。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;巧的是我通过Q先生发的微信推送里得知了他前一天也去看了《一出好戏》。Q先生没有写影评，唯有一句发自内心的感叹：“好想谈恋爱！唉！”我看完顿时笑出了声。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;……就我，我也不能客观全面地去评说这部电影，我也希望不这样做。我希望在这方面可以自我一些，直抒胸臆。道理性的话大家都懂，就看谁说得高深些，漂亮些……<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;“我也想有一场恋爱呢，让我在这个世界里始终求真，让我不畏现实，都能积极面对。我知道恋爱能给我带来多大的力量，此刻，我真的很想谈场恋爱呢。”<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;第二天正午，Q先生转发了匡扶摇的漫画————《被折角的人生或书》。漫画奇长无比，也是我第一次耐心看完匡扶摇的作品。“啊……这是对我们这些孤独的人的又一次阐释”是我的直接感受，另一方面，它像是在我脸上来了一次重击：“算了，别谈恋爱了，还是读书吧。”<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;怀想上次重大的失恋前后，我一直都保持着阅读的好习惯，我的心在任何时候都很宁静，可以安心地读完一本书，刷完一套题，看完一次展。以至后来确定一个研究方向，成绩稳步上升，顺利考得证书，结交了新的朋友等等。这么一想可能并不是失恋使我成长，而是阅读陪我孤独。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;不过谁知道哪对因果才是正确的呢？让我把话题延展开想想……每天，我都在接触新的资讯，眼界好似开阔，但是辨证来看也是一种糟糕的影响————我还没来得及去将改变的理念付诸实践，新的信息就又来了，我的理念又要更新和修订。长此以往，不做整理，我的心和脑一团乱麻。不想去整理，不想去矛盾，我手里的快餐以同样的方式端给其他人，我沦落为单纯的交换媒介。我知道这空虚、无趣，我选择按下开关，把这些“信息快餐”屏蔽，返璞归真：去追一个偶像，去学一part舞蹈……我想这才是我的“真”吧。<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;如果说原来是现实的贫富差异把我们掏空，现在可能就是无尽的信息和数据把我们掏空。希望我们都不会被掏空，希望我们不会成为新时代的“血汗工人”。而我则不想被每天的那些访问数量、浏览记录所捆缚。数据不能说明什么，一条消息说明不了什么，那坚持了小半年的游戏也只有一个段位作为纪念。希望我们能在现实中相见，即使只是沉默相对。</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/21/%E4%B8%80%E5%87%BA%E5%A5%BD%E6%88%8F/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decision</title>
      <link>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/10/%E5%88%9D%E6%AC%A1%E8%A7%81%E9%9D%A2/</link>
      <guid>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/10/%E5%88%9D%E6%AC%A1%E8%A7%81%E9%9D%A2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 12:45:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;h1 id=&quot;预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;网
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！"><a href="#预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！" class="headerlink" title="预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！"></a>预告篇———初次见面，请多指教！</h1><blockquote><p>网名：Joanne127<br>  坐标：Shanghai<br>这里引入一个小故事————appetizers<br>  我喜欢构建自己的小世界。我起初尝试了微信公众号的移动载体。<br>  要说经营一个“小空间”，我还是有足够信心。就在上面发布了我的陆续（几篇）小文之后，我感到了无力与挣扎，是斟酌字句的挣扎，是美化观感的无力。<br>  在那个宽度受限的小屏幕里，我不想阅读大量的文字，但是我自己也懒得“经营”。我不知道公众号编辑文章是不是有markdown。新媒体上手容易，有无数种让你方便编辑的插件，可是换个平台又是“新的方便”，这个方便的世界里自成一片生态园，却不是我想要的。<br>  编辑文字，从未让我觉得如此束缚。我在电脑上敲下每一句，每一段。想着自己有没有说错话，写了又删，删删删删删……<br>  总之我不喜欢这个载体，它让我不自由，短短几周后被我弃置了。<br>  我想想，再具体些……或者说，再功利些……我是想构建自己的认知体系。<br>  我考虑了很久之后，还是决定用“博客”，并且审美要求我不去用“现成”的博客网站。<br>  我挑了条最费时间的路，<br>  所以你才能看到现在的“我”。<br>  我和朋友提到在建博客的事，ta吐槽道“好怀旧的东西”，我的脑海里相应浮现出x浪博客的老旧界面，我又看了看自己从零搭建起的简约页面，就回了ta一句“挺好玩的”。</p><blockquote><p>我想说，这是个不错的开始。希望你看完这些也这么觉得。</p></blockquote><p>这里梳理一下我想写的东西————entrees<br>我是个兴趣广泛的人，虽然不知道自己爱不爱学习，但是我喜欢“终身学习”这个观念。<br>下述只能算是大类划分，也是我通常会接触的几个范畴，今后会在博客上道道的这些那些。</p><ul><li>电影</li><li>金融</li><li>数学</li><li>计算机</li><li>书籍</li></ul><blockquote><p>愿你我至真至理，共同进步！晚安。</p></blockquote></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://yoursite.com/2018/08/10/%E5%88%9D%E6%AC%A1%E8%A7%81%E9%9D%A2/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
